Chengcheng.
澄澄
No!
完了
In such a quiz,
這麼個小考
the seats are arranged according to the student number.
還要按學號排位置
I can only count on you.
我只能靠你了
Me?
靠我
Are you crazy?
你喪心病狂吧
I don't even believe in myself.
我都不相信我自己
How can you count on me?
你還靠我
What to do?
那怎麼辦
You’d better
你啊 有這時間
review for a while.
趕緊多看會兒書吧
Make as much effort as possible
臨時抱佛腳
at the last moment.
能多學點是一點
Put the books away.
可以把書收起來了
Get ready for the exam.
我們準備考試吧
Good luck to you.
好好考試
Those in front pass the papers.
前面同學把卷子傳一下
Which one?
哪題啊
The last two questions.
最後兩題
I didn’t answer them.
沒寫
You did.
寫了
I don’t know.
我不會
What?
什麼
I don’t care.
無所謂
Come on.
無語
I don’t know.
我不會
Show me.
給我看看
The one in blue.
藍衣服這同學
She said she doesn’t know.
她說她不會
Can't you hear her
她那麼大聲
talking so loudly?
你聽不見嗎
How about you ask me?
要不你來問我
Of course I know.
我肯定會
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Will our scores
我們這次的成績
be canceled?
該不會要被取消了吧
I’ll ask.
我去問問
Will our test scores
我們考試成績
be canceled?
是不是取消了
You'll know when the results come out.
成績出來你就知道了
It would be too late.
等成績出來就晚了
Could you tell me now?
你可以現在就告訴我嗎
I didn't pass a
我跟那同學
ny answers to her.
什麼答案都沒有傳
Also,
還有
senior Jiafa
平時都是加法師兄
usually came to invigilate the exam.
來監考的
Why are you here today?
為什麼今天是你來啊
Is it because
是不是因為
today is my exam,
今天是我考試
so you came here on purpose to make fun of me?
所以故意過來看我笑話
It was my mistake
我之前非要拉著你表白
to confess to you before, sorry.
是我做錯了 對不起
You did the experiment
那你實驗也做了
and played a trick on me.
整我也整了
What else do you want me to do?
你還想讓我怎麼樣啊
Come on.
來來來
Are you okay?
沒事吧 沒事吧
Man, are you okay?
哥 沒事吧 沒事吧
I’m fine.
沒事
I will help you.
拉你起來
No need.
不用
It’s okay.
沒事
I can get up myself.
我自己來
Are you sure?
可以嗎
It’s okay.
沒事 可以
Really?
真可以啊
Yes.
可以
Help him.
扶一把
No need.
不用不用不用
I can get up myself.
我自己來就行
He can make it myself.
他可以他可以
You should go.
他不用 你們走吧
It’s okay. He can make it myself.
沒事 他不用
We are leaving then.
那走了 真走了
Do me a favor.
幫個忙
Give me a hand.
拉一把拉一把
Thank you.
謝謝
You are welcome.
不客氣 沒事
Go to class.
上課吧
Delete it.
你刪掉
Chengcheng, be quiet.
澄澄 你安靜點啊
Su Chengcheng.
蘇澄澄
if you move again,
你要是再亂動的話
I'll dye your pink hair
我就把你的死亡芭比粉
black.
變成挑染黑了啊
Sorry.
對不起 對不起
It’s so funny.
真的太好笑了
When will Li Meizi come back?
李梅子什麼時候回來啊
I really want to share
我好想跟她分享
my happiness with her.
我的快樂
Forget it. I'll forward it to her.
算了 我轉發給她吧
I’m not talking to you.
不跟你說
I’m now...
我正在
Dongmao.
東茂
Didn't you want to invite that
你不是要約那個
junior Huang from the Department of Civil Engineering
土木工程系黃師妹
to watch the concert?
看演唱會
Did she agree?
答應了嗎
Of course.
那必須的
She’s so happy.
她老高興了 我告訴你
Really?
是嗎
Then what?
然後呢
Then I gave her
然後我就把兩張票
both tickets.
都給她了
I just want her to be proud
我就是想讓她
in front of her roommates.
在室友面前多長長臉
You gave her both?
你都給她了
Dongmao, seriously...
東茂 不是我說你 真的
Your emotional intelligence
情商這塊 真的
is so high.
你拿捏得死死的
Of course.
那必須的
Listen, you have to learn from me
我告訴你就這方面
in this regard.
你還是得向我學習
I will teach you when I have time...
有時間我就多教
Right.
對對對
Come on.
你快來
Look, is this Xiao?
你看這是不是小肖
He...
他他他
Why is he sitting in the trash can?
他為什麼坐垃圾桶裡呢
My gosh.
我的天哪
Go ahead.
接著笑
You are back.
回來了
I sent you a video.
我給你發了個視頻
Take a look. So funny.
你看一眼 笑死我了
What video? I didn’t see it.
什麼視頻 沒看到啊
I sent it to you.
我給你發了
No.
沒有啊
[Brain LAB - Mice Have Babies]
我發到
I sent it
我們實驗室群裡面去了
Check how long it has been.
你看看多長時間
Can you withdraw it?
能不能撤回
I am on it.
撤著呢 撤著呢
[You recalled a message]
撤回了 嚇死我了
Come on.
快快
Why is it withdrawn?
怎麼撤回了
She sent it to the group?
她發群裡了嗎
-Yes, take a look. -Let me see.
發群裡了 你看看
This is Xiao Yuhe.
這是肖宇河
From now on, this will be
這以後就是我
my reason for threatening Xiao Yuhe.
威脅肖宇河的把柄
Do you know what is
知道什麼叫
the art of war?
戰爭的藝術嗎
Nuclear deterrent.
核威懾
Your editing is amazing.
你剪輯得也太牛了
Right?
厲害吧
Yes.
有
Don’t shoot me.
別別別 別拍我
Chengcheng.
澄澄
You scared me.
嚇死我了
Don't just think about
你別光想著
fighting against Xiao Yuhe.
跟肖宇河鬥氣了
Aren't you going
你不是馬上
to be voted soon?
就要投票了嗎
In case your vote is not passed,
萬一投票不過
have you thought about what to do?
想過怎麼辦嗎
I got it!
我想到辦法了
Why can't it be recovered?
怎麼就恢復不了了呢
No way.
不行啊
Senior Jiafa, morning.
加法師兄早安
Chengcheng.
澄澄
When did you
你
dye your hair back?
頭髮什麼時候染回來的
Yesterday.
昨天染的
From then on, I will be
從此我就是一個
a simple, quiet
樸素 恬靜
and low-key girl.
又低調的女孩子
How can you have bread for breakfast?
你早餐怎麼能吃乾麵包啊
It’s bad for your health.
你這乾麵包對身體不好
Insufficient protein intake
蛋白質攝入不夠
can lead to malnutrition.
那是會營養不良的
This is the tofu jelly from the second canteen.
這是二食堂的豆腐腦
Freshly made, with a long aftertaste,
新鮮出爐 回味悠長
well-received, and the supply exceeds the demand.
飽受好評 供不應求
I
我呀
also prepared
還給你準備了
various seasonings for you.
各種各樣的調料
Whether you want it
不管你是吃甜口
sweet or savory,
還是吃鹹口
your requirement will be satisfied.
都包您滿意
Take a try.
試試
Junior Chengcheng.
澄澄師妹
You scare me
你這樣
like this.
會讓我有一絲絲的害怕
Prof. Du asked everyone
杜老師不是說
to vote on whether I can stay
這週五讓大家投票表決
this Friday.
看我是不是能留下來嗎
After thinking about it,
我思來想去吧
I feel that the possibility
都覺得我能留下的
of me staying
可能性
is really slim.
實在是不是特別大
So I decided to change tack.
所以我決定改變方針
I want to do better
我要為師兄師姐們
for seniors
多做一點好事
and leave a good impression.
讓大家給我留個好印象
In this way, my chances of success
這樣我成功的機率
may be a little higher.
可能就大一點了
My current slogan
我現在的口號就是
is Humble Su Online Services.
卑微小蘇線上服務
Do you think it will work?
您看我這個架勢可以嗎
Chengcheng.
澄澄啊
It's okay to do good.
做好事是可以的
But you don’t have to
但卑微呢
be humble.
就沒有必要了
With me here,
有你加法師兄在
what are you afraid of?
你怕什麼
I will definitely vote for you.
我肯定會投你一票的嘛
It's useless for you alone to vote for me.
只有您投我也沒什麼用
There are so many people in the laboratory.
實驗室這麼多人呢
You have one vote.
您就一票
Although there are quite a few people
咱們實驗室的人
in the laboratory,
雖然不少
only these nine people
但是一般參與投票的
generally participate in the voting.
只有這九位
As long as you get more than half of the votes,
只要票數過半
you can stay.
你就可以留下
Me.
我
Dongmao.
東茂
Zhang Li.
張力
Xiang Hui.
向輝
Dazhuang.
大壯
As long as I can get
只要我能幫你爭取到
these five votes for you,
這五票
you can stay.
你不就留下來了嗎
You are really
啥也不說了
my true friend.
真朋友
Now what I am your true friend,
既然是真朋友
could you grant me
能不能滿足朋友的一個
a little wish?
小小的願望呢
What wish?
什麼願望
Send me Xiao's video.
把小肖的視頻轉給我
Now I can finally
這下終於可以
appreciate it with ease.
從容地欣賞了
What are you watching?
看什麼呢
I...
我 我
We are talking about learning.
我們在探討探討學習
Show me.
給我看看
It’s none of your business.
關你什麼事
It's almost time to vote.
馬上要投票了
What should I do?
我該怎麼辦呀
You have to work hard
你要努力
to find your own value.
找到自己的價值
Chengcheng.
澄澄
If you have nothing to do today,
你今天要沒事的話
go to the monkey house
你一會兒去猴房
to collect some data for Prof. Du.
幫杜老師采幾組數據
This is the experiment code.
這是那個實驗守則
Just follow it.
到時候你按這個來就行
There are monkeys in our lab?
咱們實驗室還有猴子
Of course.
那當然了
The neurons of monkeys
因為猴子的神經元
are very similar to those
跟咱們人類神經元
of human beings,
很接近
so the research objects
所以一般的研究對象
are always monkeys.
都是猴子
Okay.
好
By the way,
對了
The monkey in the laboratory
咱們實驗室那隻猴子
is named Jianming,
叫建明
very smart and lively.
很聰明 也很活潑
Be careful
所以你跟它
when you come into contact
接觸的時候呢
with it.
多加小心
-Okay. -Remember to ask me
好
if you have any question.
記得來問我啊
Okay.
好
Here comes
展現我個人價值的機會
the opportunity to show my personal value.
這不就來了嗎
She will not fall in love with you.
她是不會愛上你的
Hello.
你好
Are you Jianming?
你是建明是嗎
You can even stand up.
你還會站起來呢
Hello, Jianming.
你好啊 建明
My name is Su Chengcheng.
我叫蘇澄澄
So cute.
好可愛啊
What are you doing?
你在幹嘛呢
Watching cartoons?
看動畫片嗎
Is it fun?
好看嗎
Have a banana.
吃個香蕉吧
How can you snatch the key?
你怎麼能搶鑰匙呢
Senior Jiafa.
加法師兄
I haven't been here for a few days,
我這幾天沒來
and there is a newcomer in our lab?
咱們實驗室來新同學了
An undergraduate junior.
來了個本科的師妹
Why does our lab
咱們實驗室
accept undergraduates?
怎麼收本科生了
Does she have good grades?
她成績很好
Not really.
那倒沒有
Then why?
那為什麼
She confessed to Xiao.
就是她跟小肖表白
And Xiao
小肖就把她
recruited her to the lab.
招到實驗室來了
Really?
是嗎
Does senior Xiao like her?
那小肖師兄喜歡她嗎
I don’t understand.
這我就不明白了
It’s complicated.
太複雜了
I’m not good at this.
這方面我不太瞭解
Xiao.
肖
Data.
數據
Thanks.
謝了
Senior.
師兄
These are the medical records
這是我這幾天
I collected in the First Affiliated Hospital
在第一附屬醫院
in the past few days.
收集的病歷資料
Take a look.
你看一下
By the way,
對了
I got my thesis review comments.
我論文審稿意見回來了
But I still don't understand
但是我還是有幾塊地方
some places,
不太明白
and I don't know
也不知道
if my understanding is correct.
自己理解得對不對
Could you
可以麻煩你
take a look for me?
幫我看一下嗎
Okay.
好
Thank you, senior.
謝謝師兄
I'll email you in a moment.
我一會兒發你郵箱
Anything else?
還有事
I heard that you recruited
聽說你新招了一個
a new undergraduate junior.
本科學妹啊
Why didn’t I see her?
怎麼沒看見她人呢
Well...
那個
I sent her to the monkey house.
我叫她去猴房了
I’m in charge
猴房工作
of the work
不是一直都是
in the monkey house.
我在負責嗎
She wasn’t trained,
她也沒有經歷過培訓
so she can’t make it at all.
根本負責不了
I think she's smart.
我覺得她挺聰明的
If she is inexperienced, help her more.
沒經驗你就多幫幫她
Okay.
好
I’m going to help her.
那我就去幫幫她
Dongmao.
東茂
How could you send her directly
你怎麼能讓她
to the monkey house?
直接就去猴房啊
Well, I...
不是 我
I saw she had nothing to do,
主要看她也沒事幹
so I let her go.
我就讓她去了唄
Jianming.
建明
Let me tell you
我最後跟你好好地
one last time.
說一次
Spit out
你趕緊把鑰匙
the key now.
給我吐出來
Listen.
我跟你講
I also have a bad temper.
我脾氣也很差的
If you give me the key,
你把鑰匙給我
we'll be even.
咱倆扯平了
Here.
給
Are you Su Chengcheng?
蘇澄澄是吧
How could you
你現在怎麼能把建明
let Jianming out?
放出來呢
Senior.
師姐
It was Jianming
是建明搶了
who snatched the key in my basket
我籃子裡面的鑰匙
and came out by himself,
自己出來的
not me.
不是我給它放出來的
Sorry, senior.
師姐 對不起
Su Chengcheng.
蘇澄澄
Now
你現在趕緊把建明
put Jianming inside.
再放回去
I’m working on it.
我 我一直在努力呢
Senior.
師姐
Go back.
這這 你回去啊
Get in.
你進去啊
It hits me, so I’m afraid.
它打我 我不敢呀
What’s this?
這是什麼
Screw.
螺絲
Bingo.
回答正確
It’s a screw.
這就是一顆螺絲
And
並且
it's a screw coming out
是從可憐的建明的嘴裡
of poor Jianming's mouth.
吐出來的螺絲
It’s okay that
讓你去做行為
you didn’t do a good job.
你做不好也就算了
But how can you cause Jianming
你怎麼能導致建明
to eat the screw?
吃螺絲呢
Listen.
同學
Fortunately, he spit it out.
這幸虧是吐出來了
If not,
這要吐不出來
do you know how serious
你知不知道
the consequences would be?
這個後果有多嚴重
how much energy
我們培養一隻
and effort
實驗用的猴子
it takes
需要花費多少精力
to raise an experimental monkey?
和多少心血嗎
Sorry, professor.
對不起 老師
I didn’t do it on purpose.
我不是故意的
I don't know why Jianming
我也不知道為什麼建明
suddenly reached out
它突然就伸手
and took the key away.
把鑰匙拿走了
Chengcheng.
澄澄同學
You got me wrong.
你誤會了
I didn't call you here
我叫你來啊
to listen to your explanation.
並不是要聽你解釋的
We're about to vote for you.
馬上就要給你投票了
You better be mentally prepared
你做好心理準備
and conduct yourself well.
好自為之吧
Xixi.
溪姐
Senior Xixi.
西溪師姐
Would you like some coffee?
你喝咖啡嗎
There is a new coffee shop
學校附近
near the school,
新開了一個咖啡館
and the pour-over coffee there tastes good.
做的手衝可好喝了
I packed one for you.
我幫您打包了一杯
Would you like to try it?
您要不要嘗一嘗
I don’t drink coffee, thank you.
我不喝咖啡 謝謝啊
You haven't had breakfast yet, have you?
沒吃早飯吧
I bought sandwiches and milk.
我買了三明治還有牛奶
If you want Chinese food, I have tofu jelly.
中餐的話有豆腐腦
I’ve had breakfast.
我吃過了
Xixi.
溪姐
Prof. Du said that this Friday,
杜老師說這週五
the members in the lab will vote on
讓實驗室的人投票表決
whether I can stay.
我是不是能留下來
Could you vote for me?
您看您能不能投我一票
No, no, no.
不不不
Don't go there.
別走那兒啊
Go ahead
等這毛球過去了之後
after the hairball passes.
你再走
Sorry.
對不起
This one.
這個嗎
Yes.
對
There is
這下面有個
a special effect prop below.
那個特效道具不是嗎
Let me.
我弄吧
You have to grasp the core,
你要抓住它核心
find out the key,
找出它的關鍵
and figure out the changes
摸清它棋盤上
on the board.
的變化
And you can pass easily.
這很容易就過了
Look, here is the prop.
你看這道具就出來了吧
Pass!
過了
Sorry.
對不起
I didn’t do it on purpose.
我不是故意的
I won’t do this again.
我再也不敢了
I’m leaving.
我這就走
I won't bother you anymore.
我再也不打擾你了
I will vote for you.
之後會投你的
Really?
真的
Thank you, senior.
謝謝師姐
Do you need any more help?
你還用我幫你嗎
Su Chengcheng.
蘇澄澄
How many people
你給多少人
have you shown my videos to?
看過我的視頻啊
Take a guess?
你猜呀
Senior Zhang Li.
張力師兄
I bought one milk tea
我買奶茶的時候
and got one free.
買一送一
Try if it tastes good.
你嚐嚐好不好喝
-Okay. -I will open it for you.
好
Thank you.
謝謝
Xiao, Prof. Du is looking for you.
肖 杜老師叫你
I...
我
Drink less milk tea.
你少喝奶茶
It's too sweet.
那太甜了
It's sugar-free.
這無糖
I'd better go get a cup of coffee.
我還是去泡杯咖啡吧
Good.
不錯
After the algorithm iteration this time,
這次演算法迭代之後
the recognition accuracy rate
識別精準率
has increased by more than 20%.
提高了二十幾個點
The editors of several core journals
好幾個核心期刊的編輯
are asking me.
也都在追著我問
Sort it out
那你就儘快整理一下
and send it as soon as possible.
早點發出去
Okay, I see.
行 我知道
Xiao Yuhe.
肖宇河
I watched the video
你 你那個是不是
of you falling.
那摔跤視頻
Is your waist okay?
腰沒事吧
I’m fine.
沒事
My waist is fine.
我這腰沒事
Has anything
最近一段時間
happened recently?
有沒有發生什麼
No, nothing.
沒有 什麼都沒有發生
All going well.
一切正常
Are you sure?
你確定
Yes.
我確定
Prof. Du, I will leave you alone.
杜老師 那我先出去了
Hold on.
等一下
Here you are,
給
Take it.
拿著
How about I apply it for you now?
要不我現在就幫你黏上
No need.
不用不用不用
I’m leaving.
我先出去了
It’s okay.
沒事
No need.
不用
I...
我
I have two tickets
我呢 這兒有兩張
for the weekend premiere.
週末首映禮的票
Would you like
你可不可以
to watch with me?
和我一起去看
How is it?
怎麼樣
No problem.
可以 沒有問題
Seize the opportunity
趁現在人少
while there are few people now.
抓住機會
Go.
上
Come on.
加油
Senior Xixi.
西溪師姐
What’s up?
有事嗎
Well, I know
那個 我 我知道
you like science fiction films.
你喜歡看科 科幻片
I have two tickets
那個 我這兒有兩張
for the weekend premiere.
週末首映禮的票
Would you like to...?
你要不要
Would you like to watch it with your friend?
要不要和朋友一起去看
Thank you.
謝謝
But I have an appointment for the weekend.
但我週末有約了
All right.
好吧
It's not that I couldn't say it.
我不是說不出口
I did it on purpose.
我是故意的
Of the many boys
之前跟西溪師姐
who have confessed to senior Xixi before,
表白的那麼多男生
which one has succeeded?
哪個成功過
I did so
我這麼做
to preserve a sliver of possibility.
是保留一絲可能性
In this way,
這樣的話
the chance of success will be greater.
成功機率才會大嘛
I mean it.
真的
Those boys who confessed to her before
之前跟她表白那些男生
were all blacklisted.
都被拉進黑名單了
To confess directly is to court death.
直接表白就是在送死
Stop chatting.
別聊了
The class will begin.
準備上課
Time to study.
散了散了
Let’s see today’s key points.
來看一下今天的重點啊
Write these down in the notebook.
這一塊記到筆記本上
Prof. Du.
杜老師
You scared me.
嚇我一跳
Why looking at me?
你看什麼
What are you looking at?
你在看什麼呀
I'm watching Su Chengcheng.
我在看蘇澄澄
Doesn't she
你說難道
realize it?
她就意識不到嗎
She’s making a lot of noise
她一個人在實驗室裡邊
in the lab,
上躥下跳的
which greatly affected
鬧鬧哄哄的
other students.
多影響別的同學啊這是
I think it’s fine.
我覺得挺好的
Nonsense!
好個鬼
Obviously she has nothing to do.
這明顯這就是閒得慌
Well.
這樣
Ask her to go to the Equipment Center
你讓她去器材中心
and bring over
讓她把新到的小鼠墊料
the newly arrived mouse padding.
搬過來
The mouse padding is quite heavy.
那小鼠墊料挺重的
She can’t make it alone.
她一個人搬不了
Well.
這樣吧
I’ll go with her.
我陪她一塊去吧
What do you mean?
什麼意思
Don’t you have any code
你是代碼不夠你敲的呀
or thesis to write?
還是論文不夠你寫的呀
Do you also have nothing to do?
你是不是也閒得慌的呀
It’s okay.
沒事
Let me know if you have nothing to do.
你閒得慌你告訴我
I have many things
我有很多事
to arrange for you.
可以給你安排
Why is there one copy less?
怎麼少了一份呢
So weird.
奇了怪了
I missed one copy.
怎麼少打一份啊
[Receipt and Loan System of Experimental Teaching Instruments]
同學 你仔細看看
The school stipulates that
學校有規定
to borrows these experimental instruments,
本校單位要是借用
the units of the school
這些實驗儀器的話
have to fill in
必須憑藉這個
the instrument loan application form.
儀器借用申請表
And the form
這表上
should be with the signature
還必須有你們單位的
and seal of the person in charge of the unit.
負責人的簽字和蓋章
Professor, please make an exception
老師 您通融一次
in my favour.
您幫幫忙行嗎
I will definitely send it to you.
我肯定會給您送來的
I promise to
蓋章
send the sealed form today.
我今天保證送過來
I’m begging you.
求求您了
It's no use begging me.
你求我也沒有用
Without a seal,
你這兒沒有蓋章
how can I know
我怎麼知道
if you are impersonating?
你是不是冒充的
Right?
對不對
If anything happened,
而且你這要萬一出了事
who would take the responsibility?
誰能負得起這個責任
Come in.
進來
I'm really not impersonating, professor.
我真不是冒充的 老師
-Xiao. -Prof. Tao.
小肖
I’d like to borrow a spectrum analyzer.
我想借頻譜分析儀
Spectrum analyzer?
頻譜分析儀
Okay, wait a minute.
好 你稍等我一下啊
Thank you.
謝謝
-You are welcome. -Let me.
沒事沒事沒事
Okay.
好
Thank you, Prof. Tao.
謝謝陶老師
You are welcome.
不客氣不客氣
Professor.
老師
He has
那他這
no application form,
他都沒有申請表
let alone signature
更別提什麼簽字
and seal.
還有蓋章了
Why did you give it to him so casually?
您怎麼隨便給他呀
Xiao has been in our school
小肖在咱們學校
for many years.
多少年了
He has borrowed instruments
這前前後後借儀器
so many times.
借了那麼多次了
Everyone knows him.
誰不認識他
By the way, Xiao.
對 小肖
Her procedures
正好這個女同學
are not complete.
她手續不齊全
But
那個
she said you are from the same lab.
她說是你們實驗室的
Do you know her?
你認識嗎
Yes.
認識
-We are from the same lab. -Not quite familiar.
我們真的是一個實驗室
No wonder I have never seen her.
難怪難怪 生面孔
I will go get the padding for you.
行 那我去給你拿墊料
Hold on.
稍等一下
Thank you, professor.
謝謝老師
Thank you.
謝謝
Padding weighs a lot.
墊料可是很重的
You are also going back to the lab.
那你也要回實驗室
Do me a favor.
你幫我搬一下唄
Then delete the video.
那你把視頻刪了
No.
我不
Bye.
再見
There are more.
還有啊
Seriously?
還有
The last two packs.
再有這兩包
All your padding.
都是你的墊料
It must be heavy.
很重吧
How about this?
你要不這樣
Delete the video.
把視頻刪了
I'll take care of the rest for you.
剩下的我幫你搞定
Why should I
那麼寶貴拍的視頻
delete the precious video?
我為什麼要刪
I don’t need you.
用不著你
How about I give you one-on-one tutoring
我幫你一對一輔導
to ensure your smooth graduation?
保你順利畢業怎麼樣
One on one?
一對一
If I study with you,
我不如不畢業呢
I might as well not graduate.
跟你學
Sir.
大爺
Your tricycle...
您這車
Beauty.
美女
Senior.
師兄
Thank you for revising the paper
昨天修改論文的事情
for me yesterday.
謝謝你啦
Never mind.
沒事 不客氣
Senior.
師兄
Anything I can do for you?
那有什麼我能幫忙的嗎
How about I
要不我幫你
check the electrode caps for you?
清點一下電極帽吧
We’ll have
今天
a lab class today.
不是剛好有實驗課的嗎
Su Chengcheng has finished
電極帽
checking the electrode cap.
蘇澄澄已經清理完了
Senior Dongmao.
東茂學長
I really envy junior Chengcheng.
我可真羨慕澄澄學妹啊
She has only been here for a few days
這才來了沒兩天
and she has integrated into the group.
就跟大家打成一片了
I heard that
聽說
she insisted on entering our lab
她非得進咱們實驗室
because she wanted to fall in love.
就是因為想談戀愛
She confessed her love to senior Xiao
這才跟肖學長
after meeting him
沒見兩天面呢
only a few times.
就主動表白了
Girls nowadays
現在這種女孩子
are more and more
可真是思想
open minded.
越來越開放了
I asked Su Chengcheng
實驗室
to come to the lab.
是我讓蘇澄澄來的
It's not that she wanted to come herself.
並不是她想來
Don’t look at me like this!
你 看什麼看
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Did you go get the mouse padding?
你去取小鼠墊料了呀
Come on.
來吧
I'll help you carry them upstairs.
我幫你搬上去
Great.
太好了
I was struggling how to move them upstairs.
我正愁怎麼搬上去呢
Take the big one.
那你搬那個大的吧
I'll take care of the two little ones.
我搬這倆小的
Okay.
好
Gu Chen, thank you today
顧晨 今天謝謝你啊
for doing me a great favor.
幫我這麼大一個忙
I'll treat you to milk tea another day.
改天請你喝奶茶
Okay, deal.
行 我記著了
I’m going back.
那我先回去了
Sure, take care.
好 你去忙
Bye.
再見
Senior Jiafa is so handsome.
加法師兄好帥
Three wheels
這三個輪子
are smoother than two.
就是比兩個輪子絲滑啊
Where did you borrow it from?
你從哪裡借的
I borrowed it
我是問那個
from the scrap collector.
收廢品的大爺借的
Just charge it up
等咱們用完了
when we're done.
給人家充好電就行
Junior Chengcheng.
澄澄師妹
I really admire
你這個每次都能
your core skill to survive
狹路逢生的核心技能
from a desperate situation every time.
真是讓我敬佩敬佩呀
Not at all.
沒有沒有沒有
Senior.
師兄
You look so good here.
你在這兒特別好看
I’ll take a picture of you.
我給你拍張照
Come on.
來來來
Senior Jiafa.
加法師兄
Give others a chance.
不能老你一個人騎吧
Let me try.
讓我試試
Come on.
你來你來你來
I’d also like to try.
我也來我也來
You first.
你先你先
Let me.
我先
Come on.
來來來
I’ll take a picture for you.
一會兒拍給你們看
I’m also coming.
我也來我也來
I will try.
我也試試
Take a group photo.
合張影合張影
Come on.
來來來
Senior, would you like to come over
師姐 你要不要也過去
and take a photo together?
一起拍張照片
Come on, get on.
來來來 上去
Okay, come here.
行 那你來你來
Su Chengcheng.
蘇澄澄
Not only do you not work yourself,
你自己不工作就算了
but you also affect others.
還影響別人
No wonder senior Xiao is so tired of you.
怪不得肖學長那麼煩你
The stuff for the monkey terrarium
猴類飼養室的東西
has arrived.
已經到了
Pick it up on the tricycle.
你就騎著三輪車取吧
Okay, I see.
好 我知道了
Anything else?
那您還有別的事嗎
No.
沒了
Senior.
師姐
What?
幹嘛
I have something to tell you.
我跟你說個事啊
You...
你這個
Stay away from me.
去去去 你離我遠點
No, you...
不是 你
What are you doing?
幹嘛
You got chocolate on your teeth
你 牙上沾上巧克力了
and it's dark now.
現在黢黑
I didn’t mean it.
不是
It was she who asked me to stand away.
她非得讓我站遠點
Chengcheng.
澄澄
Take another photo for us.
再幫我們拍一張
Ready.
來
One, two, three.
一 二 三
Are you going to return the equipment?
你這還器材去啊
It’s so heavy.
你這夠沉的
How about I let Su Chengcheng
要不我讓蘇澄澄
go with you?
跟你一塊去
I look so ugly.
我好醜啊
Look for it.
找一下
Look for the photo I took just now.
找一下前面我拍的那個
Much better looking than yourself.
那比本人好看多了
No way! Look.
你哪有 你看
Look at the legs.
你看這腿
No need.
不需要
So powerful.
這麼猛嗎
I am so pissed off.
氣死我了
Hello, Musk.
你好 馬斯克
Hello, Xiao Yuhe.
你好 肖宇河
Scan starts.
開始掃描
Scan is over.
掃描完畢
Musk.
馬斯克
Why can Su Chengcheng
你說蘇澄澄
gather a large group of people
為什麼幹啥事
no matter what she does?
都能招呼一大幫人呢
She has been like this since she was a child.
她從小就這樣
But she's so cute
不過她那個嘚瑟勁吧
like this.
還挺可愛
Chengcheng, good for you.
澄澄 可以呀
Our lab has been discussing you
我們實驗室一上午
all the morning.
都在討論你
The photos of you riding a tricycle
你騎三輪車的照片
went viral all over the school.
都火遍全校了
Li Meizi.
李梅子
They
他們呀
only saw my outward beauty,
只看到了我面上的風光
but they didn't see the tears behind.
沒有看到我背後的淚水
Let’s go.
別說了 趕緊走吧
Come on.
走
So dark.
好黑呀
Why are the street lights
今天這路燈是怎麼回事
all off today?
怎麼都滅了
They must be broken.
壞了
Slow down. Watch your steps.
你慢點啊 看著點地
Isn’t this...?
這不是
He seemed to be deliberately
他好像故意
lighting the way for us.
給我們照路哎
How could he
他怎麼可能
light the way for me?
故意給我照路
He wished
他巴不得我在黑暗裡面
I would stumble in the dark.
摔一大跟頭吧
Look, we gave way
你看呀 我們都讓路了
but he didn't leave.
他也沒走啊
Are you two made peace?
你倆又和好了吧
How come?
神經 誰跟他和好
Don’t look back.
你別往後看了
Stop looking back.
別回頭看了
No worries.
別著急啊
Why are you walking so fast.
走這麼快幹嘛
Look.
你看
He is lighting the way for us.
他就是給我們照路